我希望这门课涵盖了很多领域，让你能够深入挖掘，
I hope this class covered a lot of ground for you to be able to dig deeper in,
我希望它告诉你在哪里以及如何使用东西。
I hope it showed you where and how to use things.
我希望你看够了，这样你就可以说好吧，我不知道，好吧
I hope you saw enough of it so that you can say okay i don't know it, okay it
是的，这么多，但我有一些练习我可以查找，我有我可以的例子
was so, so much but I have some exercises I can look up, I have examples I can
查找，我可以为工作选择合适的工具，并在需要时深入研究。
look up and I can choose the right tool for the job and dig in when I need to.
这就是这门课的目的。
That's that's kind of the purpose of this class.
马克这是怎么了？
What's that up Mark?
&gt;&gt; 似乎 TypeScript 在这里真的很有帮助。
&gt;&gt; It seems like a TypeScript would be really helpful here.
你有没有 - &gt;&gt; 是的。
Do you have any- &gt;&gt; Yes.
&gt;&gt; 你可以抬头看？
&gt;&gt; That you could look up?
有资源吗？
Any resources?
&gt;&gt; 是的，所以那里有一些人，
&gt;&gt; Yeah so there's a few people out there,
我可以发布他们的 Twitter 句柄句柄，但是
I could post their Twitter handles handles but
他们正在推动 TypeScript 所以
they're pushing TypeScript so
到目前为止，这就像让 JavaScript 感觉像 Scala。
far that it's like making JavaScript feel like Scala.
他们对类型所做的事情真的令人印象深刻，
And it's really impressive what they're doing with types,
我打算在 TypeScript 中开始这门课，因为它更容易拥有
I was gonna start this class in TypeScript cuz it is a lot easier to just have
类型检查器说，你在两者中都有一个函数，
the type checker say, you have a function inside of neither,
这不是你说你会给我的。
and that's not what you said you would give me.
但是你必须特别使用 TypeScript 的很多类型技巧，
But a lot of the type tricks that you have to do with TypeScript in particular,
TypeScript 不喜欢承诺之类的东西，
TypeScript doesn't love things like promise,
拿着一个要么拿着一个，你就知道一个任务。
holding an either holding a, you know a task.
它不是为此而构建的，您必须做一些解决方法才能使其正常工作，
It's not built for that and you have to do some some workarounds to get it to work,
它的功能越来越丰富，但最终却变成了很多类型
it's getting more feature rich but, it ends up being a lot of type
让它同意这些超级嵌套类型的技巧。
trickery to get it to agree with these super nested types.
所以我强烈建议使用它，但如果你要深入研究类型，
So I highly recommend working with it, but if you're gonna go that far into types,
考虑您的环境，考虑与您一起工作的人以及
consider your environment, consider who you're working with and
想一想，此时我是否应该只使用类型化的函数式语言。
think about, should I just use a typed functional language at this point.
或者我应该使用 TypeScript，因为我处于我需要的环境中
Or should I use TypeScript because I'm in a setting where I need
而是使用 TypeScript。
to use TypeScript rather.
&gt;&gt; 你是说像 Elm 还是纯粹的纯剧本或理性？
&gt;&gt; You mean like Elm or pure pure script or reason?
&gt;&gt; 没错，你可以用 Elm，你可以用成绩单，你可以用的理由，
&gt;&gt; Exactly, you could use Elm, you could use transcripts, use reason you can use,
还有十几个[笑]在那里。
there's a dozen more of those [LAUGH] are out there.
有编译到，但主要的是，如果你正在学习
There's compiled to, but the main thing is, if you're learning
范式本身，你可以在每种语言和所有地方看到这些东西。
the paradigm itself, you see this stuff in every language and all the places.
Elm 正在积极尝试不去这里，但人们仍在这样做，
Elm is actively trying not to go here, but people are still doing this,
[笑]同样的事情，你可能会被理性绊倒，
[LAUGH] and the same thing, you might get tripped up in reason,
他们有一个来自旧 Camel 的 func 类型，它是一个模块函数。
they have a func type it comes from old Camel, it's a module function.
它与这个函子的定义不同，
It's not the same definition as this functor,
即使它仍然植根于一些相同的术语很酷。
even though it's still rooted in some of the same terminology cool.
非常感谢大家来上课，
So thank you all so much for for attending the class,
如果有任何问题和我可以帮助发布的内容，请告诉我。
let me know if there's any issues and stuff I can help post.
[笑] 我会把所有的代码都贴出来并修复任何小错误
[LAUGH] I'll post all the code up and fix any little bugs so
当您下载它时，它实际上会运行。
it'll actually run when you download it.
[笑] 非常感谢。
[LAUGH] Thank you very much.
&gt;&gt; [掌声]
&gt;&gt; [APPLAUSE]